# 这家伙 哪个外国总统（来了）
When a foreign president (comes)
# 别给上牛扒 来盘土豆丝儿 吃美了
Don’t serve steak, but instead, serve this shredded potato; that’s wonderful
# 土豆丝我提前切出来了
I have shredded potatoes in advance
# 辣椒面待会耗个小红油
The chili powder will be used to make red chili oil
# 两种辣椒面 细辣椒面跟粗辣椒面
Two different types of chili powder, fine- and coarse-grained
# 芝麻也给炒出来了 熟芝麻
The sesame has been cooked
# 香菜呢 香菜切好了
How about the cilantro? Already cut
# 别使这香菜 别使叶儿
Don’t use cilantro leaves
# 就用点梗才漂亮呢出来
The dish is more beautiful if we only use cilantro stems
# 来 咱们先炸点红油
Okay, let’s cook some red chili oil first
# 第一步 葱的下脚料 炼点小葱油
Firstly, use the unused green onion parts, to make some onion oil
# 往里头稍微加点水 辣椒面加水
Add a little water into the chili powder
# 它不容易糊 这是个小窍门
A tip to avoid burnt
# 咱们炸一个简易版的小红油
Let’s make a simple version of red chili oil
# 拿热油沏上辣椒面
Pour the hot oil on the chili powder
# 耗上 开始咱们准备炸土豆丝
Let’s prepare to fry the shredded potatoes
# 咱把土豆丝水空出去
Let’s pour the water away
# 八成油温 咱就少下
Eighty percent of the oil temperature, so let’s fry less initially
# 分两锅到三锅
Fry 2 or 3 times
# 这个我们要跟网友提示一下
Here I want to hint our friends
# 土豆丝要漂漂水
The shredded potatoes must have been washed
# 因为里边的含粉量比较高
Because potatoes have too much starch inside
# 不漂水的话一会就上色了
The color will quickly turn brown if the potatoes have not been washed
# 刚才我这个冲了有半小时
I have flushed them with water for about half an hour
# 在家为了省水换水也可以
In order to save water at home, we could also wash and change water several times
# 这个油温就是八成油温
The oil temperature is eighty percent
# 在咱家的灶就是大火
When cooking at home, we use high heat
# 在饭店的时候就是小火 沁炸
While in restaurant, we use low heat
# 炸成金黄色 把水分给它逼出去
Fry to golden color, to get rid of the water
# 您这也差不多了 漂起来
Looks almost done, take them out
# 必须垫厨房用纸 吸油
Must use kitchen towel to absorb oil
# 看着油多 其实没那么多油
The oil looks like a lot, but actually not
# 所以说油温必须得够
So the oil temperature must be high enough
# 土豆丝炸好了啊 金黄色
The frying is done, golden color
# 刚才师父说了 香菜得用梗
Master just said, we must use cilantro stems instead of leaves
# 香菜梗清爽利落 叶容易塌
Cilantro stems make the dish look more clean, while leaves is contrary
# 会影响菜的美观
Will affect the presentation of the dish
# 寸段
Cut into cun (~3.3 cm)
# 行了
Okay
# 辣椒段 小火慢慢煸一下
Chili segments, cook a little with low heat
# 这会儿关火了开始
Turn off the heat
# 关火一定关火
Must turn off the heat
# 土豆丝下锅 加味喽
Add the shredded potatoes into the pot, now begin to add seasoning
# 白糖
Sugar
# 盐 少了点再来一点
Salt, not enough, add a little more
# 为什么关火 开着火就糊了
Why need to turn off the heat? Otherwise the shredded potatoes will be burnt
# 这土豆丝本身就是熟的了
Note that the shredded potatoes have already been cooked
# 白胡椒粉
White pepper powder
# 少搁点香油
A little sesame oil
# 香油来点
A little
# 这时候葱丝该撒上了
Now add the cut leaves of green onion
# 红油搁不搁啊 待会搁师父
Whether to add the red chilli oil now? Add it soon, master
# 搁吧现在
Add it, now.
# 红油搁的时候咱得用一下篦子
We need to use a sieve
# 少撒点红油
Don’t add too much red chilli oil
# 香菜 扒拉扒拉就出来了
Add cilantro, just mix them up to finish the cooking
# 这时候开一下大火
Now use the high heat
# 稍微一颠就行了
Just toss the wok several times
# 香菜的味都出来了
The aroma of cilantro is out
# 金黄色  这时候该关火了
Golden color, now turn off the heat
# 撒上熟芝麻 刚才我炒的 出锅了
Sprinkle the sesame I cooked just now, done
# 水一定擦出去
Must get rid of the water
# 听着就酥脆
Listen, already crispy
# 你看搁点颜色（红油）对了吧
Look, it makes sense to add some color (red chilli oil)
# 为什么是香辣土豆丝啊
Why aromatic and spicy shredded potato
# 插一筷子它就不爱倒了
Look, it won’t collapse if we insert a chopstick
# 就跟盖房子似的 有根龙骨了
Just like building a house, it has a joist
# 这龙骨就是大爷
Da Ye is the joist
# 咱再轻轻的给拿下来
Let’s take the chopstick away lightly
# 好了 齐活
Okay, done
# 您老哥俩尝尝
You two brothers have a taste
# 好吃
Delicious
# 酥脆 咸香 微辣 葱香 香菜香
Crispy, a little spicy, mixed aroma of salt, green onion and cilantro
# 芝麻的香 辣椒的香
And the aroma of sesame and chili
# 红油的香 土豆的脆
The aroma of red chili oil, the crisp of potatoes
# 很普通一个土豆丝
An ordinary shredded potato dish
# 能做的这么精彩 这么有味道
can be so wonderful and delicious
# 虽然国宴菜是国宴菜
Even though state banquet dishes are from the state banquet
# 但是我们要把家常菜做好了
But if we could cook homestyle dishes well
# 也能上国宴
They can also show up in the state banquet
# 这家伙哪个外国总统（来了）
So if a foreign president (comes)
# 别给上牛扒
Don’t server steak
# 来盘土豆丝 吃美了
But instead serve this shredded potato; that’s wonderful
# 这网友问说
Some friends ask
# 能讲讲炒糖色吗
Can you talk about how to make caramelized sugar
# 还有拔丝炒糖
And syrup coating dishes
# 老是操作不好
Always fail
# 炒糖色的
To make caramelized sugar
# 糖最好用冰糖
It’s better to use white rock sugar
# 它出来以后颜色红亮
The final color will be more red and light
# 说如果没有冰糖怎么办
What if we don’t have white rock sugar
# 我们就用棉白糖
We could choose soft white sugar
# 或者是砂糖
Or the granulated sugar
# 如果是棉白糖的话
If you are using soft white sugar
# 就锅底儿把锅要烧好
We first need to heat the pot
# 溜一溜
Make the pot hot enough
# 放点底油
Then add some base oil
# 把绵白糖下锅
Add soft white sugar in
# 因为你的锅是热锅
Because your pot is hot
# 要凉油
You need cold oil
# 所以刚开始起火的时候
So at the beginning,
# 别太大 等糖化了以后
Don’t use high heat; when the sugar becomes melted
# 它冒的是大泡
It has big bubble initially
# 白色的
White
# 然后慢慢的经过加温
After heating slowly
# 开始变中火
Change to medium heat
# 这糖就开始变色了
When the color begins to change
# 有点黄色的了
to a bit yellow
# 这个节骨眼是拔丝的火候
It’s the perfect time for making sugar coated dishes.
# 继续往下找
But if you continue heating
# 炒的跟酱油色似的
The sugar color will be like soy sauce
# 有点冒烟了
And even begins to smoke
# 好
Okay
# 这时候旁边准备一点
Now prepare some
# 温水
Warm water
# 一看冒烟了
Once it begins to smoke
# 色也跟酱油色似的
And the color looks like soy sauce
# 把水迅速的倒进去
Pour the warm water in immediately
# 这就是糖色
This is the so-called caramelized sugar
# 但是糖色这个环节
But during making caramelized sugar
# 这糖拿勺搅起来
If you try to mix the sugar with a wok spoon
# 很快就回落到锅心里面去了
You will find the sugar falls back the middle of pot very fast
# 不是那种冒泡的了
It’s not like bubbling anymore
# 就特别稀
It is very sparse
# 而且颜色也很重
And the color is also very deep
# 而且还冒烟
And it smokes
# 过了火就有点发苦
It will become bitter if overcooked
# 先把糖色取出来
We could take the cooked caramelized sugar out first
# 然后我们再把肉解（冻）好了
And after we thaw the meat
# 然后再回锅再炒
Then put the caramelized sugar back to cook
# 逐渐的再加强起来
Enhance gradually
# 这糖色就炒好了
The caramelized sugar is done